

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

453. São Francisco de Paula St. Boa Vista - Novo Hamburgo - RS - Brazil

□ (+55) 51-99708-6600 | **□** brunoklein99@gmail.com | **□** brunoklein99 | **□** brunoklein99

Summary.

Current Software Engineer at SAP. 6+ years experience in backend development for cross-industry projects. Also, strongly focused on Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Big Data. Likes to be at the forefront of tools and technologies.

Experience_

SAP São Leopoldo, Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Apr 2018 - PRESENT

- Developing and dealing with several Machine Learning able solutions with both structured and unstructured data, supervised and unsupervised. As of now, mainly focused on Natural Language Processing.
- Fine tuning of word embeddings for domain specific use.
- · Used existent research to deliver a state of the art correlated timeseries forecasting model built with PyTorch.
- · Created microservices for face recognition (FaceNet based) and face detection (TinyFaces based).
- Team lead engineer.
- · Docker & Kubernetes.
- Python / TensorFlow / Keras / Scikit Learn / xgboost / GoLang.
- SOLID and DRY enforcer / Code reviewer.
- Setup of Travis CI/CD pipeline
- · Nominated for the highest employee award

DeepX Porto Alegre, Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Feb 2018 - Apr 2018

- · Elixir and functional programming.
- Docker & Kubernetes.
- Event Notification and Event Sourcing, Kafka based (Martin Fowler's version/definition).
- · Brought an entire Microservices system on top of AWS using Kops, before the release of Amazon's EKS.

Health4TheWorld Palo Alto, California - Remote

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Nov 2017 - Nov 2018

- Developed a Deep Learning (ResNet based) model for image regression able to accurately infer a person's age based on chest X-rays.
- Developed a Deep Learning (U-Net based) model for ICH (Intracranial hemorrhage) segmentation.

Server - Retail Software Novo Hamburgo, Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun 2013 - Mar 2018

- Application Profiling and optimization with both 3rd party and in house tools.
- Database migration from Firebird to Postgres.
- Database and SQL queries performance tuning, in some instances up to 10x improvement.
- Developed several APIs and clients for integrations, both RESTful and SOAP based.
- Developed ERP modules and integrations with customer factory systems, bank systems and government systems.
- Code owner of a few mission critical routines (related to law compliance, accounting and government)
- · Consistently delivered dozens of complex ERP modules, including an order fulfillment optimizer based on a distributed customer inventory.
- · Application telemetry for in production monitoring and debugging.
- Database modeling and normalization/denormalization of complex and crucial business problems.

Education

UNISINOS (Universidade do Vale do Rio dos Sinos)

São Leopoldo, Brazil

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jan 2013 - Dez 2019

Skills.

Programming Python, PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, SQL, GoLang, Docker, Kubernetes

Languages Portuguese (Native), English (Advanced)

Publications

INTERNATIONAL

 $\textbf{Proceeding, BRACIS 2019,} \ Self-Adaptive \ Appearance-Based \ Eye-Tracking \ with \ Online \ Transfer$

BRACIS 2019

Learning